PERSONAL INFORMATION



Sayed Habibullah Hossaini

- Pekrabad, Herat, Afghanistan, 3000
- +93789963000
- xayed.habibullah.h1@gmail.com
- Skype ID: https://join.skype.com/invite/Jxt1k1p0tPQ6
- WhatsApp: https://api.whatsapp.com/send?phone=+93789963000

Sex Male | Date of birth 23/03/1994 | Nationality Afghan

WORK EXPERIENCE

24 September 2018 to on going

Habib Latif Hossainy Ltd / Running my own company.

Habiblatifhossainyltd@gmail.com

- Works with the board of directors and other executives to establish short-term objectives and long-range goals, and related plans and policies.
- Presents regular reports on the status of the company's operations to the board of directors and to company staff.
- Oversees the company financial structure, ensuring adequate and sound funding for the mission and goals of the company.
- Reviews the financial results of all operations, comparing them with the company's objectives and taking appropriate measures to correct unsatisfactory performance and results.

Business or sector: Private

8 May 2019 to on going

Youth Savior Foundation/ Running my own Foundation

youthsavior.scf@gmail.com

- Developing and implementing growth strategies.
- Training low-level managers and staff.
- Creating and managing budgets.
- Improving revenue.
- Hiring employees.
- Evaluating performance and productivity.
- Analysing accounting and financial data.

Business or sector: Private

18 June 2017 to 16 Sep 2018

Coordinator of Educational Seminars/ Women Civil Advocacy and Economical Development Organization

Women.caedo@gmail.com

- Organizing seminars for children and women
- Holding legal seminars and citizenship's rights responsibilities
- Women's rights awareness
- Organizing workshops
- Holding reading sessions
- Youth capacity building sessions

Business or sector: Private

9 May 2016 to 10 May 2017

Lecturer / Sana Kosar Institute

- Initiate, facilitate, and moderate classroom discussions.
- Evaluate and grade students' class work, assignments, and papers.
- Compile, administer, and grade examinations, or assign this work to others.
- Prepare course materials such as syllabi, homework assignments, and handouts.
- Maintain student attendance records, grades, and other required records.
- Advise students on academic and vocational curricula, and on career issues.

Business or sector: Private

02 June 2017 to 02 June 2018

Lecturer / Khaja Abdullah Ansari University

- Planning teaching, including lectures, seminars/tutorials and learning materials
- Meeting students individually to discuss progress
- Checking and assessing students' work
- Interviewing potential students
- Carrying out administration, such as attending faculty meetings and writing reports
- Writing research proposals, papers and other publications
- Managing research budgets
- Preparing bids for funding for departmental research projects.

Business or sector: Private

2 April 2016 to 26 March 2018

Master trainer/ Herat Subat People Stability Council

- Contribute to the overall quality of the project by continuously monitoring the progress of the project's outcomes and the quality and relevance of the curriculum.
- Contribute to M&E efforts in coordination with the project manager and support staff.
- Continuously inform project participants about extra services provided within the auspices of the project.
- Contribute to the evaluation of the curriculum at the end of the project for the purpose of enhancing the training materials for future use.
- Responsible for participant's coordination, enrolment and documentation (Attendance sheets, registration sheets, etc...)

Business or sector: Private

24 March 2015 to 25 March 2016

Legal Advisor / Cube and Line

Employer: Mr. Fatullah Email: cubeandline@gmail.com cell phone: +9378542758430

- Overseeing client and vendor contracts
- Conducting legal research
- Drafting basic legal documents for construction projects
- Ensuring compliance to construction laws and regulations
- Preparing damage claims
- Providing arbitration, litigation and mediation support
- Advising on the latest building standards
- Business or sector: Private

15 Feb 2014 to 15 Feb 2015

Community Mobilizer / Line Social Org.

Employer: Sharifullah Karamat Salar, Email: kkaramatsalar@gmail.com Cell phone +93700046788

- Provide the related trainings to the right holders.
- Facilitate interest and self-help groups in communities with a focus on poor men and women and marginalized and excluded groups
 - Facilitate and support the distributions in the community level.
 - Assess training needs of the right holders in mid-stream and adjust refresher training.
 - Any other official tasks given by line manager.
 - Reports to Project Coordinator.
 - Conducting a detailed assessment of the communities.

Business or sector: Private

8 February 2012 to 10 February

Logistic Officer/ Shakohi Construction And Logistic Services Company

Employer: Toryalia Zalmai, Email: <u>zalmai@wassa.org.af</u> Cell phone +93730288709

- Updating inventory lists.
- Receiving and dispatching goods and verifying movements of stock.
- Checking purchase orders against stock levels.
- Preparing delivery schedules.
- Coordinating maintenance and repairs of storage facility.
- Entering data into a database.
- Maintaining optimal stock levels at minimum cost.
- Calculating storage and clearance costs.

Business or sector: Private

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

March 2014 to December 2017

Bachelor of Law and Political Science

Jami University, Herat, Afghanistan

- Percentage: 88.2
- Research on "Studying Rumi's Political Thoughts"

1 September 2017 to 1 Sep2018

Diploma of English

Ghalib University, Herat, Afghanistan

14 April 2018 to 14 April 2020

Diploma of Pharmacy

Ghalib Institute of Health Sciences, Herat, Afghanistan

03 April 2002 to 22 Sep 2013

High school

Ustad Riaz High School, Herat, Afghanistan

Research and Publications

- Studying Rumi's Political Thoughts, Jami Publication of Jami University
- Investigation Of Politics in the Intellectual System of Maulana Jalaluddin Muhammad Balkhi Rumi
- Religious Pluralism in The Thought of Maulanan Jalauddin Muhmmad Rumi
- Explaining Afghanistan-Turkey Relationships Based on the School of Constructivism.

PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue(s) Other language(s)

Persian

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
C2	C2	C2	C2	C2
English National and International Certificates				
B2	B2	B2	B2	B2
83 out 120				

English

Pashto

TOEFL IBT Score

Levels: A1/2: Basic user - B1/2: Independent user - C1/2 Proficient user Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

Communication skills

Good Business Communication

Organisational / managerial skills

Job-related skills

Leadership

Good command of quality control processes

Computer skills

- Good command of Microsoft Office[™]
- Fast English and Persian Typing

Other skills

- Time management
- Communication
- Setting goals
- Delegation
- Working under pressure
- Self-motivation
- Analytical thinking
- Attention to detail
- Decision-making
- Strategic planning

Profile

I highly motivated individual with extensive experience in the national organizations; solid practical knowledge in Administration and Human Resources I also worked as a manager, officer, advisor, Institutional strengthening and capacity building in teaching social science, English and Public speaking.